## **ALVIN JACKSON**

# SENIOR UX & UI PRODUCT DESIGNER

Creating harmony between a product, a user, and a business is very essential. I am a strategist that tailors a well-documented plan to build a solution for all team members, users, and stakeholders. With the challenging ever-changing requirements of people, products, and industries I thrive in creating meaningful successful applications.

Experienced in remote work and open to relocate or come in office if needed.

#### Address:

70 Lost Meadow Trail The Hills, TX 78738

P: 737-206-0715

E: hello@alvinjackson.com W: www.alvinjackson.com

### **SKILLS & TECH**



#### **UI DESIGN**

8+ yrs. creating experiences in Invison, Adobe XD & Suites, Basalmiq, Axure, Sketch and Figma.



#### HTML & CSS

3+ years building responsive using Visual Studio, Github, Bootstrap, Javascript, and more.



#### LEAD

Working with developers, designers, and stakeholders using Trello, Jira, Zoom, Skype, Slack, and Azure.



#### **UX & RESEARCH**

8 + years creating user flows, journeys, and more. Invision, Flowmapp,Overflow, Miro, Mural, and Adobe.



#### **DEVELOP & LAUNCH**

Coordinating with dev. team, finalize designs, speed test, micro details, A/B testing, and launch.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 10+ YEARS OF CREATING AND LEADING

#### **INVENTIVE WORKS, LLC**

Senior UX and UI | January 2019 - present

Assist in the creative direction of the user experience and design regarding application interface. My work is a compilation of UX strategies (flows, JTBD, and stories) which are then transitioned into UI design using Adobe XD for prototypes and style guide libraries, and Adobe suites for visual marketing and launch materials. Using Jira, Miro, Zoom, and Slack ensures strong team communication, as we take design mockups, prototypes, and development to meet aggressive deadlines for enterprise applications in an Agile environment for companies like Assurant, Prograde Digital, and Texas A&M College.

#### **VESTOR POCKET, LLC**

Senior UX & UI | May 2017 - January 2019
Recent Projects | SA Shoe & Company, Livestock Loader, LLC, DebonaireU

For start-ups and other companies, I did research regarding strong data analysis, user stories, and user flows. Exploration and design then take place using wireframes, style guides, and mockups with tools Sketch, Basalmiq, Adobe XD, and Invisionapp for small companies and Start-Ups in an Agile and Scrum environment when needed. The user approved prototype and design elements are then pushed to the developers. Once the product is developed quality testing and launch are accomplished for updates. Much print work and branding in Indesign and Adobe Suites was also used I did to help the launch phase of products.

#### FIRST UNITED CORP.

Senior UX and UI | March 2017 - February 2018

Through an extensive marketing campaign, I created the user experience and design of websites and multiple landing pages to help bring profitable leads for all investors within the firm. I designed, implemented content, analyzed competitor web pages and websites for A/B testing, and generating a good user experience that helped bring profitable leads. The environments used were Adobe, Google Analytics (user data and testing), Invisionapp, Sketch (style guides), and Wordpress for landing pages.

#### **MEDIAFUSION DIGITAL MEDIA PLATFORM**

Lead UX and UI | September 2016 - March 2017

As lead designer, I created the user experience and interface of a Netflix style application that could easily be added to their customer's website. This project contract also entailed me creating all marketing and branded materials using Adobe Suites. Skills and technologies used: HTML, CSS, Basalmiq, Wireframe, Sketch, Invisionapp prototyping, Jira, Adobe Suites.

#### **ALVARA GROUP, LLC**

UI & UX | March 2011- April 2016

As Product Designer & Lead with Alvara Group, I lead many projects consisting of enterprise projects like Hearst Media that needed an in-house product that maximized profits and production. The daily work consisted of team collaboration, interviews, research, and design. Skills used: Jira, Sketch, Balsamiq, Wireframe, Invisionapp prototyping, HTML, CSS, Content Management Systems, user research, and data, Adobe Suites.

#### **EDUCATION**

Nielsen Norman Group - UX Conference, 2018

Devry University - BA 2006

